If the agency said, "Okay, you're going
on this podcast. Say whatever you want.
Just work in this one thing." And that
got the wheels turning in my head.
>> Ah, that's insightful.
>> I just hadn't thought about it that way.
People claimed other famous CIA officers
are plants. I won't say who.
>> There's a couple things that are in my
head right now, but I have a feeling
people would really want me to ask you
about this. Did you Did you happen to
see Shawn Ryan on Tucker?
>> You did. Okay. So, for people that maybe
haven't, he he talks about um he
interviewed this guy that was a CIA and
FBI agent that is an asset. Sean had him
on his show. And I didn't I didn't watch
the full episode, but just for context,
let's say this guy was um his story and
his credentials were I don't know,
al-Qaeda. Let's say that, right? And
let's say that he's Middle Eastern based
and that's where his story lives. And at
one point he says something to Shawn
about it was either the Russians trying
to proliferate nuclear material or bring
nuclear material somewhere and it was
something alarming related to Russia.
And Sean talks on Tucker about he's like
well I looked at the guy and I asked him
immediately. I was like when is the last
time that you had contact with the
agency and apparently this guy's story
was that he got burned by the agency.
The agency [__] him. That's what he
claims. So he says, "Well, no, it was,
you know, when they screwed me. That was
the very last time." And Shawn goes,
"Well, I'll tell you what I'm thinking.
If the CIA found out that you were going
to come on this podcast, obviously the
Shawn Ryan show has quite a bit of reach
and he's a uh
I think there's a difference between a
show having a lot of reach and the
show's host being reputable, which in my
opinion, Shawn is. He's very reputable."
Yes. Um
>> Yeah. He's the He's the real McCoy.
>> Yes. I Dude, I modeled this whole show
off of him. I respect him a lot. I think
he's the goat. Anyway, um he asked the
guy, "When's the last time you had
contact with the agency?" Because,
>> good question.
>> He seemed he felt like he just threw
that Russia thing in there and it was
totally out of place. And the theory
would be like if the agency said, "Okay,
you're going on this podcast. Say
whatever you want, just work in this one
thing." And that got the wheels turned
in my head.
>> Wow, that's insightful.
>> I just hadn't thought about it that way.
Like you would think there people claim
other famous CIA officers are plants. I
won't say who.
Uh we don't need to go there, but just
that one nugget.
>> Mhm.
>> What do you think about that? I think
that's a brilliant insight
and I could absolutely see it. 100%
absolutely see it. Yes.
Yes. You know, people talk about
Operation Mockingbird and and the the
CIA's influence over the media.
They don't need to recruit media figures
anymore because the American media just
will gladly take whatever the the CIA
gives them and they'll run with it.
They'll just gist a a CIA press release
and call it call it news.
So, yeah. You know, a friend of mine,
Jason Leupold, I don't know if you know
Jason. He's a he's an investigative
journalist with Bloomberg. He started
off at the LA Times. He went to Vice and
a couple of other different places. This
guy is absolutely brilliant. He's a
gifted writer. He's a dogged
investigator
and breaks big stories. He's the one who
broke the Hillary Clinton email server
story. And the way he did it, the way he
does it every time is he files these
gigantic Freedom of Information Act
requests knowing that the agency's never
going to respond within the 60 days or
90 days or whatever it is. And so he
sues them every time and he wins every
time.
And so
he filed a Freedom of Information Act
request asking for
all correspondence between the CIA's
Office of Public Affairs and
all American journalists, period, from
this date to that date. And they didn't
respond. And he sued and the judge ruled
in his favor and they had to just turn
over everything. and he found such
interesting information. He found
first there was a um a reporter who
wrote a story that was a little bit
anti-CIA.
And so the CIA emailed them and said,
"You better not publish this. If you
publish this, so help me God. You will
never be invited to the Christmas party
ever again and we will not comment on
any of your stories." And so he
withdrew.
They don't need to recruit the guy to
kill the story. They just threaten him.
Another thing that he found was Ken
Delaneian, who is the chief national
security correspondent at NBC News and
MSNBC.
He was writing articles about the agency
and then he was sending the articles to
the agency for clearance before he sent
them to his own editor.
That is absolutely unacceptable.
So, they don't need to recruit anybody
in the media, they already own everybody
in the media. And if you're anti- agency
and you're not working for a well-funded
media outlet, you're screwed cuz you're
just not going to be able to get your
message out there. That's why we're so
fortunate to have people like Matt
Taibbe, for example, who's able to get
his message out thanks to Substack.
You know, we need we need a thousand
Matt Taibbe, not these weaklings who are
just going to take whatever the CIA
gives them and gist it and put their
name on the by line and then we find
ourselves propagandized by the agency.
I mean, that's the thing, man. Now that
I'm thinking about it, if you're an
independent podcaster and like me, I am
my team. I don't have a team. I don't
have a team of producers like Tucker to
try to verify
>> That's right. prior.
So, first of all, I would say the onus
is on people, individuals that listen to
what they listen to to decide what they
want to believe. That needs to be number
one.
>> And let me interrupt you on that point
cuz that's a very very important point
that I hope everybody takes to heart.
>> You can't trust anybody and so you have
to trust yourself. And the only way you
can trust yourself is to consume
everything.
You know, I get up in the morning,
people, friends of mine accuse me of
being too mainstream, and I'm actually
not mainstream. But you have to know
what the mainstream is saying so that
you can refute it. So, as soon as I wake
up in the morning, I read the Washington
Post, the New York Times, the LA Times,
the Wall Street Journal, and then I go
to CNN, Fox, The Guardian, a couple of
others. I read the Greek papers just
because I'm Greek and I have an interest
in it. And then I go to the blogs and
the substacks and stuff like that. You
have to consume everything and have
confidence in your own intellect. So you
can read something and say, "Ah, that's
[__] That's just not true." And
then you read something else, you say,
"That's plausible. That makes sense. I'm
going to watch that issue." Because who
you going to believe? You going to
believe Kendallian,
right? I'm not. You gonna believe the
Washington Post? I like uh Ella
Nakushima and Joby Warick, but then
that's pretty much it. There maybe are
one or two people at the New York Times.
Nobody at the LA Times anymore.
So, you you've got to be confident in
your own ability to discern what's true
or what's not true or you just get
overwhelmed
with what is likely to turn out to be
propaganda.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, dude. I mean, shoot. I don't I
don't know how to uh you know, I think
guest selection as a podcast host is an
important one. You can't just platform
anybody. But at the same time,
>> isn't that the truth?
>> There is an argument to be made that
again, I think, you know, each
individual draws the line as you do. You
have a show.
>> Um, and you know, it's for you or I to
say where that line is. But at the end
of the day, you know, information is out
there. Make up your mind on your own.
>> Yeah, that's it. like like uh we talked
about Scott Horton a minute ago. Um I've
become something of a like a
semi-regular on the Pierce Morgan uh
show and uh the last time I was on it
was like a last minute thing cuz
somebody dropped out. So they said, "Can
you come on in 15 minutes?" I said,
"Sure." So I I log on and I see Scott
and I was like, "Oh, thank God Scott's
here." Okay, so this is going to be a
serious discussion.
Yeah. So, he wasn't scheduled to be like
he's like a fill in, you mean? Or
>> Yeah, he and I were both fillins, but as
soon as I saw Scott Horton, I thought,
"Okay, this is going to be a serious
intellectual conversation."
>> Do you know anything? I think it was
Scott that mentioned this. Um, it might
have been Scott or Daryl Cooper,
actually. I Which Okay, I don't I don't
know what Daryl Cooper has been for.
I'll say that. I I listen to a lot of
Tucker. I I like Tucker's podcast.
>> I like Tucker a lot.
>> It was one of those
>> He goes deep, too.
>> Yeah. Say what you want about Tucker. I
don't give a [__] I'm just telling you
I listen to his podcast sometimes and
these two guys, one of them said
something about the National Endowment
for Democracy.
>> Do you know anything about that?
>> I and I believe the context was that it
was a proxy for the CIA.
>> Yeah, it is.
>> What does that mean?
>> The National Endowment for Democracy has
taken many millions of dollars from the
CIA to promote American propaganda.
uh mainstream American government
propaganda. So when it talks about
things like nation building, it's not
really talking about nation building.
It's talking about encouraging the
development of leaders in foreign
countries that are going to be knee-jerk
supporters of the US and US foreign
policy.
>> So it's mainly a
propaganda scop sort of machine for lack
of a better term. It's not like actual
boots on the ground type operations.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. Not not at all boots on
the ground. Okay. Not at all.
>> No.
>> You know, when we liberated Kuwait in
1991,
I I've told you in the past, I went in
with the Marines on Liberation Day. It
was very, very exciting. One of the
highlights of my life, my adult life.
And then within days of Kuwait being
liberated, these Americans just kind of
show up and
they came to the embassy to register and
then we would bump into each other at
events.
Remember the country is literally on
fire. The Iraqis had blown up all the
oil wells and there are these giant, you
know, 100 foot high flames gushing out
of the ground. It turned out these
people were from the Democratic National
Committee and the Republican National
Committee. I'm like, "What are you doing
here?" And they said, "Well, oh, we're
here to help them transition to
democracy." Well, it's a it's a
monarchy. It's not going to be they have
this little elected, you know, melatani
and national assembly, but it's not
going to ever be democratic.
Well,
I was in my 20s then, not really savvy
enough to know that this is all part of
the plan. You use the National Endowment
for Democracy. You use, you know, NPR,
you use the DNC and the RNC, and you all
smile and get along and go to cocktail
parties, and it's all just to promote
American propaganda. I I worked with a
guy briefly, John Rendan, God bless him,
awesome guy, and I asked him one time,
this is before he hired me to do a
contract. I asked him what he did. He
said, "Oh, I'm a professional
propagandist."
I said, "What does that mean?" And he
said, 'Well, you were in Kuwait on
liberation day.' And I said, 'Yeah.' He
said, 'You remember when the American
tanks are rolling down the the main
street, the Cornesh? I said, ' And he
said, and a million people are out there
waving little American flags. I said,
yeah. He said, where the hell do you
think those flags came from?
The country's destroyed. It's it's
Liberation Day, but everybody has
American flag and they're all waving
their little flags.
And I was like, you know what? I never
even thought of it. Mhm.
It's good living in propaganda.
>> What's up, guys? Thank you so much for
taking the time to watch the interview.
If you got anything out of this video at
all, please like the video, leave me a
comment, tell me what you thought of the
video, uh, tell me who you'd like to see
on the show. I really appreciate the
support. It goes a long way on these
platforms, as you guys know. Most
importantly, I have some excellent
interviews coming up in the future that
I'm really, really excited about. So,
please subscribe to the channel so you
don't miss any of them. But that's it.
Thank you for your support. I really
appreciate it and hope to see you again